Joe Herbert

https://joeherbert.dev

07449056469 - joe@joeherbert.dev - Warwick



Personal profile

I'm a 23 year old Software Developer based in Warwick, with a 1st Class BSc in Computer Science and experience as a freelance full-stack web developer. I have a passion for problem solving, which has driven me to create many projects since my first "Hello World!" back in 2014. I'm a highly self-motivated individual, who is quick to learn and is fascinated by the advancing capabilities of technology. I love working with people and meeting others with shared interests, such as sports or photography.

Technical skills

JavaScript - HTML - CSS - Node.js - MySQL - WordPress - GitHub - SEO - Web Extensions - PHP -Swift - Python - Java - Haskell - R - C++ - C# - VB.NET - Bash - SVG design

Work experience

Jul 2018 - Present (Part-time)

Freelance Web Developer

Creating tailored websites for local businesses, including:

- Full stack developer for Best CPC Training creating a website including a booking and payment system.
- Full stack developer of a bespoke CRM storing confidential information for Molly Olly's Wishes (a national children's charity) using Node.js, Express and MySQL.
- Front end developer of a static site for Primary Tutoring Warwick using HTML, CSS and JS.
- WordPress developer and manager for Molly Olly's Wishes and Edward's Boys (a renowned acting company).
- Developed two websites (The View and Hill Farm Marina) for two connected businesses in Warwickshire using Wix.

Aug 2020 - Sep 2023 Bartender/Waiter - The Durham Ox/Gorcott Hall Weddings

(Part-time)

- Co-ordinated with other members of small teams in fast-paced environments, balancing multiple jobs while prioritising the customer's experience.
- Improved my social skills by talking to people while serving them, forging relationships with regulars and coworkers.

Oct 2018

Software Developer – SCC

(Internship)

- Added functionality to internal software, increasing efficiency.
- Attended meetings as part of a development team.

Aug 2017

Programmer - REPL

(Internship)

- Expanded a silent auction app for a local charity using C# and MySQL.
- Used AGILE planning and wrote user stories.
- Learnt about programming in a team and working to deadlines. Gave daily updates on my progress, and a final presentation of my work.

Education

Sep 2020 - Jul 2023

Computer Science Bsc, Hons. 1st Class - University of Liverpool

- Averaged over 80% in all modules, which included: functional programming, OOP, database development, financial computing, iOS app development, e-commerce, robotics, AI and high performance computing.
- My dissertation was an iOS app for reviewing entertainment venues, built in Swift with an accompanying Node.js API and MySQL database. I received a first for this project.
- Computer Science and Cyber Security societies member.

Sep 2014 - Jun 2019

A-Levels/GCSEs - King Edward VI School, Stratford-Upon-Avon

- A-Level: Computer Science (A), Maths (B), Further Maths (D).
- Received Industrial Cadets Gold Award and Gold Crest Award as part of the Engineering Education Scheme with Warwickshire CC, completed a feasibility design for a bridge over the A46 and presented to over 80 engineers.
- GCSEs: 4 A*s, 5 As, 1 B and 2 Cs, or equivalent.

Other interests

Sep 2023 – Sep 2024

Travelling

- Interrailing around Europe, visiting 32 cities in 14 countries, meeting people from all over the world.
- Driving a campervan around Australia and New Zealand.

Jun 2011 – Jul 2023

Badminton Player, Captain and President

- President and Treasurer for University of Liverpool Badminton Club, managing the second largest club in the university. Organised events, managed finances, solved issues and improved the club.
- Men's 1st Team Captain, achieving an undefeated promotion.
- Regularly played junior badminton for Warwickshire and competed in national tournaments, for myself and the county.
- Attended three international training camps in Denmark.
- Used my Level 1 Coaching Qualification to train younger players.

Oct 2017 - Jul 2023

Other Sports and Clubs

- Photography Society, University of Liverpool. Worked as a photographer for the Athletic Union at national events.
- Hockey: University of Liverpool Saturday Men's 2, Balsall and Berkswell Men's 2, King Edward VI School 1st Team Captain
- Windsurfing, University of Liverpool
- Maths and Physics Society, King Edward VI School, Co-founder

Oct 2017 - Apr 2019

School Extracurriculars

- Elected a Prefect by my teachers and peers.
- Experienced other cultures by visiting China in October 2017 and co-organised a Multicultural Event in March 2018 for 180 guests.
- Completed DofE Bronze and Silver awards.
- Key member of the KESDev development team.